[Road to Success]
[星のように煌めく]
[Episode 29]
[第29話]
[Goodbye, my love]
[さようなら 愛しい人]
Professor Shu.
舒教授
How very careless of you.
脇が甘いんだよ
Many years have gone by,
長年
yet you've never noticed the missing of a photo of yours.
写真をなくしたことにも 気づかないなんて
Xiang Zi,
向梓
you have no shame at all.
ほんと最低
Is it really my fault?
俺のせいか
Lin Wanxing, why don't you think about this—
林晚星 よく考えてみろよ
how did you get chosen
大勢いる中で
from so many people?
なんで君なんだ
That's pure sophistry.
言い訳しないで
Long before the candidate was decided,
推薦枠が決まる前から
you had already filmed that video in secret.
とっくに動画を盗撮してたじゃない
Your words have actually reminded me.
おかげで思い出したよ
By disguising as you that time,
あの時の変装は
I did discover many things.
かなりの収穫だったな
By the time
その時になったら
I get hold of
この女子学生と
the surveillance video of a girl student's rendezvous with a professor in a hotel,
教授がホテルで密会した映像は
this will be a permanent stain on your life.
君の人生の一生の汚点になる
Lin Wanxing,
林晚星
I must destroy your reputation.
君を破滅させてやる
Professor Shu, are you ready?
舒教授 もういいですか
Yes, I'm coming.
はい 今行きます
[Intervention in quality inspection]
[品質検査への介入]
[Measuring tool: multi-dimensional evaluation framework]
[測定ツール 多面的評価システム]
Unexpectedly,
まさか
I found out Shu Yong's secret on that occasion.
舒庸の秘密を知ることになるとはな
[Sertraline Hydrochloride Tablets]
[塩酸セルトラリン錠]
See,
見ろ
even heaven is on my side.
天も俺に味方している
It turns out you are also a patient.
お前も病人だったとはな
Isn't it great?
最高だろう
I really think all that has happened is God's idea.
すべては天の采配だと思う
Just by coincidence,
なんて偶然なんだ
I found out he had clinical depression.
あいつがうつ病だと気づいて
And so coincidentally,
そしてまた偶然
I was also the first one to discover he had committed suicide.
自殺した時も俺が第一発見者だ
Shu Yong was really stupid.
舒庸は本当にバカだな
He'd rather take his life than offer his spot to me.
自殺してでも 俺にその枠を渡さなかった
So, I decided to never let him rest in peace.
だから安らかには死なせない
As for you...
それから君
Everything started because of you.
すべての元凶は君のくせに
How could you extricate yourself unscathed?
無傷でいられると思うな
How?
なぜだ
Everyone likes you, Lin Wanxing,
林晚星 君はみんなに好かれてる
for being cheerful,
明るくて
youthful,
若々しくて
and kind.
優しい
So I decided to destroy you with my own hands.
だからこの手で全部壊してやる
I swore to push you into a mire
君をどん底に突き落として
and make sure you could never get out of it.
一生這い上がれないようにしてやる
You can use your good looks
君は美貌を武器に
to get whatever you want.
目的を果たせるなら
I have my own ways too.
俺にも俺のやり方がある
I am not the one in the wrong.
悪いのは俺じゃない
This whole world is wrong.
この世界と
Hypocrites like you are wrong.
偽善者の君たちが悪いんだ
Xiang Zi!
向梓
You've gone completely insane.
あなた正気じゃないわ
So what?
それがどうした
When this information is posted online
これをネットに流せば
and gaining traction...
じわじわと炎上する
Gossip is a fearful thing.
人のうわさは恐ろしい
By then,
そうなれば
your reputation will be ruined.
君の評判は地に落ちる
So, is this a confession now?
じゃあ認めたわね
Yes.
ああ
I admit
認めるよ
that everything was my doing.
全部俺がやった
I did all that.
俺がやったんだ
What can you do about it?
どうする
Are you okay?
大丈夫か
Wen Chengye!
文成業
Did we not invite Ms. Lin over?
林先生とは約束してないのか
No.
してない
So many things have happened lately.
最近いろいろあったから
We've discussed and agreed
みんなで話したんだ
that Ms. Lin should take a good rest.
林先生には休んでもらおうって
Let's start training.
まず練習だ
Look!
ほら
How about...
なあ
we go say hi?
挨拶でもしていこうか
I don't think she wants to be disturbed.
今はそっとしておいたほうがいい
Coach.
コーチ
Hello, coach.
こんにちは
Why is Ms. Lin
林先生
running alone?
どうして一人で走ってるんだ
Coach.
コーチ
Will we still have training today?
今日の練習は？
You're all gathered here now.
全員そろったな
Start running then.
走り始めろ
Not until Ms. Lin finishes?
林先生を待たなくていいんですか
Come on!
さあ
Is a debauched woman like her truly
あんな尻軽女のために
worthy of all your efforts?
そこまでする価値があるのか
Say it again, I dare you!
もう一度言ってみろ
Everything started because of you.
すべての元凶は君のくせに
How could you extricate yourself unscathed?
無傷でいられると思うな
How?
なぜだ
Everyone likes you, Lin Wanxing.
林晚星 君はみんなに好かれてる
So I decided to destroy you with my own hands.
だからこの手で全部壊してやる
I swore to push you into a mire
君をどん底に突き落として
and make sure you could never get out of it.
一生這い上がれないようにしてやる
When this information is posted online
これをネットに流せば
and gaining traction...
じわじわと炎上する
Gossip is a fearful thing.
人のうわさは恐ろしい
By then,
そうなれば
your reputation will be ruined.
君の評判は地に落ちる
He's just a dark and ugly rat
ドブの中の
hiding in a stinky gutter.
薄汚いネズミだけよ
Lin Wanxing,
林晚星
what is there to be afraid of?
怖がる必要なんてない
How interesting.
本当に面白い
The many difficulties I used to deem as unsolvable
昔は盤石だと思っていた 多くの困難も
now seem to be
今思えば
nothing at all.
大したことないわ
Wrong is wrong.
過ちは過ち
No one should pay for others' mistakes.
誰も他人の代償を 背負うことはできない
I'm going to sue Xiang Zi.
向梓を訴える
I will have him pay the price
彼には自分のしたことの代償を
for what he has done.
払ってもらう
Director Jia,
賈主任
we need a complete chain of evidence for the lawsuit.
訴訟には完全な 証拠の連鎖が必要です
Could you please try to recall
当時 どうやって事が 大きくなったのか
how the situation escalated back then?
少し思い出していただけますか
We hope to find some clues.
何か手がかりになることは？
At that time,
当時
many people
多くの人が
received an anonymous email.
匿名のメールを受け取りました
Then, overnight,
そして一夜にして
things started to snowball.
事態は大きくなっていったんです
By the next day,
翌日にはもう
the situation went out of control.
手がつけられない状態になりました
Do you know
では ご自身の他に
who else received the email
誰がメールを受け取ったのかを
besides you?
ご存じですか
Many other people did,
大勢います
all of which were alumni.
皆 同窓生です
I guess...
恐らく
they amounted to over a hundred.
100人以上はいるかと
Hello, I'd like to file a case.
すみません 訴訟を起こしたいです
Okay.
はい
Please submit relevant materials.
関連資料をください
Thanks to Director Jia's help,
賈主任のおかげで
we traced the source of the email.
メールの送信元が分かった
It's an abandoned account.
廃棄されたアカウントだ
[Lab Building, Yongchuan University]
[永川実験]
The IP address is located in...
ⅠＰアドレスは
the lab building of your department.
君たちの学部の実験棟だった
But we can't confirm
でも
Xiang Zi was the sender yet.
向梓だと断定はできない
More than one person received that email, right?
メールを受け取ったのは １人じゃないんでしょ
I'll go ask around on the forum
ほかの受信者が
to see if other receivers have posted anything.
投稿したかを掲示板で聞いてみる
[Shocking: A female top student came out of a professor's room at midnight]
[衝撃 女子エリート学生 深夜に 教授の部屋から出てくる姿を目撃]
[Check the video attached to the email]
[真相はメールの動画に]
[Our professor always claims himself to be a role model in the academic world]
[うちの教授 いつも学界の 模範だって偉そうにしてるけど]
[But now there's a scandal about him]
[結局 問題を起こしたんだ]
[This email has reached a wide audience]
[このメール かなり広くばらまかれている]
[It was even sent to our department's group chat]
[うちの学部のグループ チャットにまで回ってきた]
[I got it too, such provocative content]
[俺にも届いた かなり煽るような内容だった]
[But there's no solid evidence]
[でも具体的な証拠は 何一つなかった]
[This email has reached a wide audience]
[このメール かなり広くばらまかれている]
[It was even sent to our department's group chat]
[うちの学部のグループ チャットにまで回ってきた]
[I didn't receive it, but my roommate did]
[私にはないけど ルームメイトには届いていた]
[It looks like an insider wrote it]
[内部の人が書いたような 内容みたい]
[I got the email, saying crap like she knowingly became a mistress]
[私にも届いた 相手に 妻がいるんだって 冗談だろ]
[E Xiao Wu]
[額小唔]
I found a clue.
手がかりが見つかった
Altogether, over a hundred copies of this email
合計100通以上のメールが
were sent within three days
３日間に分けて送信されてて
from two IP addresses.
ⅠＰアドレスは２つ
One IP address is from the lab building of Yongchuan University.
１つは永川大学の実験棟
But the other one can't be located yet.
もう１つは不明なの
Yu Bo just told me that he found it.
余波がさっき突き止めた
The other IP address traces back
もう１つのⅠＰアドレスは
to Xiang Zi's home.
向梓の家だった
The IP addresses are different,
ⅠＰアドレスは違うけど
but the device is the same.
使われた端末は同じだ
Only Xiang Zi satisfies
両方の情報を照合すると
all these conditions.
該当するのは彼しかいない
Please fill out this confirmation form.
こちらの確認書にご記入ください
[The person to be served] [Plaintiff's signature or stamp]
[受取人 本人署名または押印 林晚星]
Alright.
わかりました
[Notice of Acceptance from the Hongjing City People's Court]
[宏景市人民法院 事件受理通知書]
The sea water feels so nice.
海水って気持ちいい
Sometimes I felt like...
時々 私はまるで
I was a statue,
彫刻みたいだって思うの
being gazed at and judged
みんなからじっと見つめられ
by those people.
裁かれてる
I thought the more they slandered me,
でも 中傷されるほど
the straighter I had to stand.
もっと背筋を伸ばさなきゃ
I must not lose.
負けられないって思ってた
But now I've thought it through.
でも 今は分かった
I don't have to be so harsh on myself.
人生って そんなに 意地を張らなくてもいいの
Being alive itself
生きてること自体
is meaningful enough.
それだけで もう十分意味がある
There is no such thing as healing in the world.
この世に 本当の治癒なんて存在しない
Pain leaves scars in our hearts.
苦しみは心に傷跡を残す
So, amidst confusion and perplexity, we need to
だから私たちは戸惑い迷う中で
hear the truest voice within us.
心の奥にある正しい声を聞くんだ
It will help us overcome all difficulties
その声が困難を乗り越えるのを助け
and keep us company for a lifetime.
一生寄り添ってくれる
This is what my therapist told me.
これは私のカウンセラーに 教わった言葉なんだ
Now, it's a gift to you too.
君と私自身に贈るよ
Let's go!
行こう
♪ Every night ♪
♪ 毎晩 ♪
♪ I reach for starlight ♪
♪ 星の光に 手を伸ばす ♪
♪ Wandering through dreams with you ♪
♪ 君と夢の中を彷徨う ♪
♪ I follow the beat of my heart ♪
♪ 鼓動のリズムに乗せて ♪
♪ Like dust floating in the air ♪
♪ 宙を舞う塵のように ♪
♪ Because of your love ♪
♪ 君の愛が ♪
♪ I shine brilliantly ♪
♪ 私を輝かせる ♪
Ivory,
白
we are back.
ただいま
I'll go handle this in the kitchen first.
先に厨房で下ごしらえしてくる
Did you miss us?
会いたかった？
We'll take you to the beach with us next time, alright?
今度 海に行く時 連れてってあげるね
Good boy.
いい子ね
Hello.
もしもし
Your dad's coming.
お父さんが来たよ
Dad,
父さん
what brings you here?
何しに来たんだ
Those are clothes.
全部 服だぞ
Clothes I bought for Ms. Lin.
林先生に買った服だ
Why did you buy these many clothes?
なんでこんなに服を買うんだよ
Ms. Lin is going to the battlefield soon.
林先生はもうすぐ 戦場に行くんじゃないか
I'm here to deliver gear to her.
装備を届けに来たんだ
She's going to court,
訴訟に行くんだ
not a fashion show.
ショーじゃない
It's so typical of you,
だからお前は女心が分からない
silly straight guy.
朴念仁め
Girls all like pretty clothes.
女の子はみんな きれいな服が好きなんだ
Right, Ms. Lin?
そうだろう 林先生
Anyway, I've brought the clothes here.
とにかく服はもう持ってきたから
Just accept them.
受け取ってくれ
Whether you'll wear them or not... It's just a kind gesture from me.
着るかどうかは別として これは私の気持ちだ
Thank you for such kindness, Uncle.
お心遣いありがとうございます
Please don't go to any expense on my account next time.
でも今後は 気を遣わなくていいですよ
You see, my tiny house
この小さな家では
can barely hold so many items.
置き場所もありませんし
I can get you a new...
なら家を…
Please don't buy me any houses, either.
家も絶対に買わないでくださいね
Well, then, Ms. Lin,
じゃあ 林先生
t-tell me what you like,
何が欲しい
and I'll buy it for you.
おじさんが贈るよ
Actually,
実は
I enjoy delicious food.
おいしいものが好きなんです
How about this?
こうしませんか
I'll treat everyone to a meal next time.
今度 私が皆さんにごちそうします
Sounds great.
いいな
I'm a food enthusiast too.
私も食べるのが好きだ
It's settled then.
じゃあ こうしよう
When you win this lawsuit,
訴訟に勝ったら
let's throw a victory party.
祝勝会を開こう
We'll provide feasts for three days and nights.
三日三晩の大宴会でも開こう
-Thank you, Uncle. -Cut that crap.
- ありがとう おじさん - 三日三晩なんてやめろよ
Dad, aren't you going to visit Yueyang Tower with Mom?
父さん 母さんと岳陽楼に行くんだろ
Hurry up and memorize the Record of Yueyang Tower.
早く「岳陽楼記」を 覚えたほうがいいぞ
I did forget about it.
すっかり忘れてた
You did, huh?
だろ
Had better get a move on.
急がないとな
Bye bye then!
また今度な
Don't buy clothes for her with your taste again.
もう父さんのセンスで服を買うなよ
Got it.
はいはい
Your dad has a more lovely personality than you.
お父さんのほうが よっぽどかわいい性格してるね
It's rare to see a wealthy
お金持ちの父親で
young man's father this amiable.
あんなに気さくな人は珍しい
How do you know
私だって年を取ったら
I won't be more lovable than him when I get older?
お父さんより かわいくなるかもしれないだろ
Ms. Lin,
林先生
you just wait and see.
まあ見てろよ
Okay.
はい
By the way, how's your preparation of materials?
そういえば資料の準備は？
Almost done.
大体できたわ
This time, I'll make sure
今度こそあのクズを
that scumbag is convicted.
地の底に叩き落としてやる
I'm more concerned about your side.
それより そっちこそ
Xiangzhen Lingshi
祥鎮霊獅は
advanced as the top of Group D.
グループＤ1位で突破したチームよ
They are not to be underestimated.
実力は侮れないわ
Don't worry.
心配するな
I'm not afraid at all.
余裕だよ
Let's cook!
ご飯作るか
Time to do some cooking.
ご飯作ってくるね
This is an announcement of court rules.
法廷規則を読み上げます
[Courtroom No. 6 for Cross-regional Cases]
[広域第六法廷]
First, all personnel present at the court session
一 全員 審理中は
shall obey the directions
裁判長または
of the presiding judge or the sole judge,
独任裁判官の指揮に従い
and observe judicial etiquette.
司法儀礼を尊重すること
Court is now in session!
開廷します
Mr. Presiding Judge,
裁判長
the plaintiff now presents the first set of evidence.
原告は第一の証拠を提出いたします
This set of evidence
この証拠は
consists of the notarized preservation of electronic evidence
著名な卒業生の メールアドレスに関する
[Notarial Certificate]
[公証書]
from the plaintiff's extinguished alumnus's email accounts,
電子証拠保全の公証書と
as well as other supporting materials.
その他の証明書類です
There are 135 emails
中には合計
in total.
135通のメールがあります
[Authorized Representative for Oral Argument] [Plaintiff]
[訴訟代理人] [原告]
The purpose of exhibiting such evidence
本証拠の立証趣旨は
is to prove that the defendant committed
被告が権利侵害行為を行い
an infringement and caused damages to the plaintiff.
原告に損害を与えたことです
[Authorized Representative for Oral Argument] [Plaintiff]
[訴訟代理人] [被告]
We can see here
ご覧のとおり
that the emails are filled
電子メールの中には
with insulting remarks and defamatory information
原告の林晚星さんに対する
directed at
侮辱的な発言や
the plaintiff, Ms. Lin Wanxing.
誹謗中傷が満ちています
For example,
例えば
the fabricated claim of an improper relationship
原告と指導教授の 不適切な関係を捏造し
between the plaintiff and her supervisor, with highly insulting remarks
極めて侮辱的な言葉を使用しており
to gravely damage the plaintiff's right to reputation.
原告の名誉権を著しく侵害しました
Moreover,
また
[Authorized Representative for Oral Argument] [Plaintiff]
[訴訟代理人] [原告]
the IP addresses from which
メールのⅠＰアドレスは
the emails were sent both trace back to the defendant's computer.
いずれも被告が使用する ＰＣを示しています
In addition, the sender's email account
さらに メールを 送信したアドレスの
is both registered to and used by the defendant.
登録者と使用者も被告です
Besides, the alumni who received these emails
加えて メールを受信した 卒業生たちは
come from all walks of life.
さまざまな業界におり
They have extensive social connections,
社会的に広い範囲に及びます
and each of them is a renowned figure
かつ各自の分野において
in their respective fields.
高い知名度を有しています
These emails
これらのメールは
not only damaged Ms. Lin Wanxing's personal reputation,
林晚星さんの個人的な名誉を 傷つけただけでなく
but also caused adverse effects
彼女が属する専門分野にも
in the field of her profession,
悪影響を及ぼしました
leading to a significant drop in the plaintiff's social evaluation,
結果として原告の 社会的評価を著しく低下させ
[Authorized Representative for Oral Argument] [Plaintiff]
[訴訟代理人] [原告]
and causing tremendous mental distress.
重大な精神的損害を与えられました
The emails also brought substantial negative impacts
また 原告の学業や研究活動にも
on the plaintiff's academic studies and research.
極めて悪質な影響をもたらしました
The defendant may
被告は
cross-examine the first set of evidence now.
第一の証拠に対し 反証意見を述べてください
[Authorized Representative for Oral Argument] [Defendant]
[訴訟代理人] [被告]
Mr. Presiding Judge, we have no objection to the authenticity of the evidence
裁判長 原告側が提出した証拠の
submitted by the plaintiff,
真正性に異議はありません
but we have doubts about its relevance.
しかし その関連性には 疑問があります
[Authorized Representative for Oral Argument] [Plaintiff]
[訴訟代理人] [原告]
It is our belief
当方としましては
that the IP addresses from which the emails were sent
メールのⅠＰアドレスが
being traceable to my client's computer
当方の依頼人のＰＣを 指していることだけでは
cannot directly prove
メールが向梓さん本人によって
that the emails were sent by Mr. Xiang Zi himself.
送信されたとは 直接証明することはできません
Yongchuan University's Information Service Center
本学の情報サービスセンターは
provides email services for all teachers and students.
全教職員と学生に向けて メールサービスを提供しています
Mr. Xiang Zi is the registered owner of the sender's email account,
向梓さんが当該アドレスの 実名登録者であっても
but there is a possibility that the account was hacked.
第三者に不正利用された 可能性はあります
Therefore, the plaintiff's conclusion
したがって 原告側が当方の依頼人を
of my client being the anonymous sender of the emails
匿名のメール送信者と 結びつけるのは
is not objective.
客観的ではありません
The defendant suggests the possibility of the account being hacked,
被告はメールが不正利用された 可能性があると主張しますが
but provides no evidence or materials
その主張について
to support this claim.
何ら証拠を提出していません
Mr. Presiding Judge, the defendant would like to state the facts again.
裁判長 改めて事実を述べます
The defendant did not insult or defame the plaintiff.
当方は原告を 侮辱も誹謗もしていません
The fact that Ms. Lin Wanxing,
林晚星さんが
as a woman of attractive appearance,
美しい容姿を持つ女性として
used her good looks
その美貌を利用し
to seduce an academic authority
学術界の権威を誘惑して
for improper academic benefits is not to be ignored.
不正な学術的利益を 得たという事実を無視できません
My client did not fabricate this claim,
当方の依頼人は でっち上げたのではなく
but revealed it as a fact based on the truth.
まさしく事実に基づいて 述べています
The defendant rests.
以上です
The plaintiff may continue to present evidence now.
では原告 証拠提出を 続けてください
Mr. Presiding Judge, please have the court noted
裁判長 被告代理人の たった今の陳述を
the statement just made by the defendant's representative.
どうか記録してください
To a certain extent,
ある程度
that statement made by the defendant's counsel
被告代理人の陳述は
already constitutes
本件メールを送信したことの
an admission of the defendant being the sender of the emails in question.
自白とみなせます
Moreover,
その上
by doing so, the defendant once again threw insulting and defamatory remarks
この法廷で再び 原告に対し侮辱的かつ
at the plaintiff in court.
誹謗中傷的な発言をしました
Now,
では これより
the plaintiff shall present the second set of evidence.
当方の第二の証拠を提出いたします
This set of evidence includes
この証拠品の中には衣類と
clothes and a wig.
カツラがあります
All of these
これらは
are exactly belongings of the defendant, Mr. Xiang Zi.
まさしく被告の向梓さんが 所持していた物です
What is shown on the screen now
スクリーンに映っているのは
is a photo of my client's
依頼人が
from when she was in university.
大学在学中に撮った写真です
A careful comparison can easily reveal
よく見比べれば分かりますが
that these clothes owned by the defendant,
被告の向梓さんの服装と
Mr. Xiang Zi, and the style of his wig
カツラの髪型は
exactly match my client's
依頼人の
outfits and hairstyle
大学時代の格好と
during her university years.
うり二つなのです
Mr. Presiding Judge,
裁判長
it is my opinion that the opposing counsel
相手方の代理人は
is creating confusion with coincidences.
偶然の一致を利用して 論点をすり替えようとしています
Indeed, these clothes belong to my client.
たとえこれらの衣類が 当方の依頼人の物だとしても
But this can only prove that he has some special hobbies.
特殊な趣味があることを 証明するだけで
It has no direct relevance to this case whatsoever.
本件とは何ら直接的な 関係はありません
Mr. Presiding Judge,
裁判長
please allow me to present the third set of evidence now.
それでは 第三の証拠を 提出いたします
This set of evidence
こちらの証拠は
[The Educational Delegation from Yongchuan University]
[永川大学教育代表団]
consists of two videos.
２つの映像資料で構成されています
One
１つ目は
[Visited and Extended Warm Greetings to Overseas Students in the UK]
[英国留学中の学生を親しく訪問]
is about an academic exchange meeting.
学術交流シンポジウムでの映像です
We can see from it that the defendant
被告には
displays
いくつか
several habitual movements with personal characteristics.
特徴的な癖があります
[The Educational Delegation from Yongchuan University]
[永川大学教育代表団]
[Visited and Extended Warm Greetings to Overseas Students in the UK]
[英国留学中の学生を親しく訪問]
However, my client does not have
しかし当方の依頼人には
such characteristic habits of movement.
そのような癖はありません
Now, let's review the second video,
２つ目の映像
namely the one involved with this case.
つまり本件に関する映像です
It can be clearly seen
ご覧の通り
that those habitual movements
被告にしかない
exclusive to the defendant
特徴的なの癖が
are actually made by the person in this video,
なんと映像の中の
who is alleged to be my client.
当方依頼人にも現れているのです
It thus shows
これにより
the person in this video
この映像の人物は
is not my client,
当方の依頼人ではなく
but the defendant, Mr. Xiang Zi.
被告の向梓さんだと言えます
[Serve the people through impartial justice]
[人民のための司法 公正な司法]
Hey.
もう
It's been so long.
ずいぶん経ったけど
How come the trial isn't over yet?
まだ終わらないのか
Let's wait a bit longer.
もう少し待とう
It should be over soon.
もうすぐのはずだ
Don't worry.
安心して
Ms. Lin
林先生は
will definitely win.
必ず勝つから
[Serve the people through impartial justice]
[人民のための司法 公正な司法]
This concludes the oral argument.
これで口頭弁論を終結します
According to the Civil Procedure Law
中華人民共和国
of the People's Republic of China,
民事訴訟法に基づき
both parties involved have the right to make final statements.
当事者は最終陳述を 行う権利があります
The plaintiff shall address the court first.
まず原告から最終陳述をどうぞ
Honorable Mr. Presiding Judge,
裁判長
everyone present in court,
ならびにご列席の皆様
frankly speaking,
正直に申しますと
suing Xiang Zi
向梓を訴えることは私にとって
is no easy task for me,
容易なことではありませんでした
because whenever I see him,
彼の顔を見るたびに
I am reminded of all the malice
この数年間で受けたすべての
aimed at me over these years.
悪意を思い出してしまうからです
I was once rather pertubed.
私は一時 不安でいっぱいでした
I wondered what would happen to me
もし今日この裁判に負けたら
if I lost today's trial.
私はどうなってしまうのでしょうか
Will what happened two years ago
２年前のあの光景が
repeat itself?
また繰り返されるのでしょうか
It took me altogether 19 years to walk the path
私は小学校から修士課程まで
from elementary school to obtaining my master's degree.
19年間勉学に励みました
But all my effort in those 19 years
しかし その19年間の努力は
and everything else I had
根も葉もないデマや
was easily ruined
穴だらけの
by a single sex rumor
いわゆる証拠によって
and some so-called evidence riddled with flaws.
すべて台無しにされてしまうのです
People like Xiang Zi
向梓のような人は
know too well how to destroy a woman.
女性を破滅させる術を 知り尽くしています
Dyeing the hair pink is equal to improper conduct.
ピンクの髪はふしだら
Wearing a short skirt is equal to an attempt at seduction.
ミニスカートなら誘惑してる
Pretty women are considered temptresses.
美人であれば妲己だと呼ばれ
Dressing plainly means this woman is just wild on the inside.
地味な格好なら隠れビッチ
Everyone loves reading gossip.
ゴシップは誰もが大好きです
As long as a woman is once rumored to be a slut,
一度でも尻軽だと噂されれば
she always will be one.
一生そのレッテルを貼られます
I do not deem myself fragile.
私は弱い人間ではありません
Two years ago,
２年前
I stood at a rooftop.
屋上に立ちましたけど
But I didn't jump off it,
飛び降りはしませんでした
because I thought of my family and friends
私を愛してくれる家族と 友人たちの顔が
who love me dearly.
浮かんだからです
I spent two years getting back on my feet.
２年かけて立ち直り
I gathered all the necessary evidence
あらゆる証拠を集め
and proved Xiang Zi fabricated everything.
すべては向梓の捏造だと 証明しました
But what's the point?
でも それに何の意味が あるでしょう
When I was back to the office,
職場に戻っても
all my colleagues were still talking about me,
同僚たちは噂話ばかりでした
Lin Wanxing, of being a promiscuous woman
「林晚星は指導教員を誘惑した
who seduced her supervisor.
ふしだらな女だ」と
The defendant once said this to me:
かつて被告人がこう言ってました
A broken butterfly
羽をもがれた蝶は
can never fly again.
もう二度と飛べない
However, today,
でも今日
I'm standing here for one exact reason:
私がここに立っているのは
I must announce to you, Xiang Zi,
あなたに伝えるためです
that I do not fear you.
あなたなんか怖くありません
On behalf of every woman being victimized by sexual rumors,
デマや性的な中傷の被害を受けた すべての女性を代表して
I am here to tell you loud and clear
声を大にして言います
that we do not fear you and your kind.
私たちは あなたたちなんか怖くありません
Your failure
あなたの失敗は
resulted from your own incompetence.
無能さが原因です
You crushed the woman you couldn't get.
手に入らないなら壊そうとし
You destroyed the competitor you couldn't beat.
競争で勝てないなら潰そうとする
Each and every thing you did
あなたの行いはすべて
was only to conceal your inadequacy and jealousy.
自分の無能さと嫉妬を 隠すためのものだったんです
And I...
そんなあなたを
Why should I ever fear someone so incompetent like you?
私が恐れる理由がありますか
The fact that I'm standing here today
今日 私がここに立っている時点で
means you've already lost.
もうあなたの負けです
Lin Wanxing, you're slandering my character!
林晚星 よくも俺を侮辱したな
Defendant, control your emotions.
被告人は落ち着きなさい
Do people like you who get by on your looks
顔だけで成り上がったくせに
even know anything about academics?
学問が何かも分からないだろ
Defendant, please watch your language.
被告人 発言は慎みなさい
Insults and abusive language are not allowed.
侮辱や罵倒は許されません
You are hereby reprimanded by this court.
当法廷はあなたに対して 厳重に注意します
She slandered me!
彼女が俺を侮辱したのに
Why do you only hush me,
なぜ彼女ではなく
but not her?
俺だけを黙らせるんだ？
This woman climbed her way up by seducing professors.
教授を誘惑してのし上がった女に
Who is she to call me incompetent?
無能呼ばわりされる筋合いはない
The malice some people in this society have towards women
この社会に存在する女性への悪意が
once made me lose the courage to live.
一度私から生きる勇気を奪いました
But now I have realized.
でも 今は分かりました
People like Xiang Zi
向梓のような人間は
are living in the sewer like rats.
ドブにいるネズミ同然です
They're trying to drag us down
私たちを引きずり下ろし
and splash mud all over us.
泥を塗りつけようとしても
But they are the ones who will always be dirty.
汚れるのは彼らの方です
We should never punish ourselves.
自分を責めるべきではありません
Plaintiff,
原告
please restrict your statement to the case.
本件と関連のある内容を 述べてください
Refrain from inappropriate wording.
不適切な言葉は慎むように
Honorable Mr. Presiding Judge,
裁判長
this concludes my statement.
以上です
Lin Wanxing, who did you call a rat?
林晚星 誰がネズミだと？
Who did you call a rat?
誰がネズミだ
Lin Wanxing, I'm telling you,
林晚星 教えてやる
if I say you're a slut,
お前は売女だと言ったら
-you'll always be a slut! -For violating courtroom discipline,
- お前は一生そういう女だ - 被告は法廷の秩序を乱したため
the defendant is ordered to leave.
退廷を命じます
Believe it or not,
見てな
I can ruin you a million times
一度お前を潰せたんだ
now that I've done it once already!
なら 何度だって潰せる
Just you wait.
覚えてろ
Lin Wanxing, just you wait!
林晚星 覚えてろ
Court is adjourned.
これにて閉廷します
The verdict will be pronounced
合議の上
after the panel's review.
判決を言い渡します
[Strive to ensure the people]
[一つひとつの司法事件で]
[Feel justice and fairness in every judicial case]
[人民が公平と正義を 実感できるよう努める]
How did it go?
どうだった？
-What's the verdict? -How did it go?
- どうだった？
According to the Civil Code of the People's Republic of China,
「中華人民共和国民法典」及び
and relevant laws and regulations,
関連する法令の規定に基づき
this court finds that Xiang Zi's actions
当裁判所は 向梓の行為が
infringed upon Lin Wanxing's right to reputation.
林晚星の名誉権を 侵害したものと認定する
Xiang Zi shall assume liability for such infringement
よって向梓は不法行為の責任を負い
and eliminate the adverse effects.
悪影響を除去しなければならない
The judgment is as follows.
判決は以下のとおり
One, Xiang Zi shall immediately cease the infringement,
一 向梓は直ちに侵害行為を停止し
and apologize to Lin Wanxing in writing
本判決の効力発生日より
on the notice board
５日間連続で
of Yongchuan University's official website,
永川大学公式サイトの掲示板
♪ Waiting for a dark cloud to pass by you ♪
♪ 一つの雲が君を過ぎる ♪
the defendant's verified Weibo account,
被告本人認証済みの ウェイボーアカウント
and the People's Court Daily
及び「人民法院報」において
♪ Listen closely to its cries ♪
♪ その泣き声を聴いて ♪
for five consecutive days, starting from the effective date of this ruling.
書面にて林晚星に謝罪すること
♪ The heavy rain will wash away your reflection ♪
♪ 大雨が君の面影をさらう ♪
The content shall be approved by this court before release.
謝罪文の内容は当裁判所が審査する
If Xiang Zi refuses to comply with the judgement,
向梓が履行を拒否した場合
this court will publish
当裁判所はネット上に
♪ And carry it toward distant scenery ♪
♪ 遠くの景色へ ♪
the main content of this judgment online.
本判決書の主要内容を掲載する
-The expenses will be paid by Xiang Zi. -To Ms. Lin Wanxing,
- 費用は向梓の負担とする - 林晚星様へ
I deeply regret my ignorance and foolishness.
私は自身の無知と軽率な行為により
♪ Every experience has its meaning ♪
♪ すべての経験に意味がある ♪
-Second, this court hopes -I also sincerely apologize for causing
- 二 当裁判所は - 林晚星様に精神的苦痛を与え
-this trial and judgement can serve -mental distress and reputational damage
- 本件の審理および判決を通じて - 名誉を傷つけたことに 心よりお詫び申し上げます
-as a warning to the public -to Ms. Lin Wanxing. I cordially hope to
- 社会に対し 他人の名誉権を尊重し - 林晚星様にお許しいただけますよう 心より願っております
[Apology]
[謝罪文]
♪ Scene by scene, they come together to form who I am ♪
♪ 一つ一つが自分になる ♪
-to respect others' right to reputation, -to be forgiven by her. Out of prejudice
- 勝手に事実を捏造して - 私は過去 偏見と衝動に駆られた行動により
-to never make or spread false claims, -and impulse, I not only hurt her dignity,
- 偽の情報を拡散することのないよう注意を促し - 彼女の人格を深く傷つけただけでなく
♪ Even the wounds that leave behind their marks ♪
♪ 傷跡さえも残しても ♪
-and to uphold a good social order -but also fueled the cyberbullying
- 健全な社会秩序およびネット環境の - 図らずもネット上での彼女への中傷や誹謗を
-and a sound online environment together. -against her.
- 維持を願うものである - 助長してしまいました
Ms. Lin Wanxing was therefore
これにより林晚星様は
♪ Have taught me how to heal myself ♪
♪ 癒やし方も教えてくれた ♪
subjected to public pressure
一般の人には耐えられないほどの
far beyond what an ordinary person could bear,
世論の圧力にさらされ
even to the extent of affecting her studies and life.
学業や生活にまで影響が及びました
♪ The love I have given, the love I have received ♪
♪ 与えた愛も 持ってる愛も ♪
I am to blame for these consequences.
この結果に対し 私の責任は免れません
Thinking back about what I said and did,
当時の言動を今思い返すと
I feel deeply ashamed and remorseful.
深い羞恥と後悔の念に駆られます
♪ Every one of them gives me the strength not to fear being hurt ♪
♪ 一つ一つが私を強くする ♪
I am willing to bear all due responsibilities for the incident,
私はその責任をすべて負う所存です
and publicly promise
そして行動をもって反省し
to reflect on and amend for my wrongdoing with actual actions,
過ちを改めることを誓います
♪ Let my tears be carried away, back into the ocean ♪
♪ 涙をさらい 海へ還る ♪
so as not to make the same mistake.
二度と過ちを繰り返しません
Apologies given by Xiang Zi,
謝罪者 向梓
♪ And blown toward flowers blooming far away ♪
♪ 遠くの 花へ吹く ♪
on March 30, 2026.
日付 2026年３月30日
Meanwhile, according to the police,
また 警察の発表によりますと
[Hongjing News]
[宏景ニュース]
♪ I fill the blank spaces of life with colors ♪
♪ 命の余白を 彩ってゆく ♪
Xiang Zi is suspected of inciting a minor to commit suicide overseas.
向梓氏の海外における 少年自殺教唆疑惑が
The case has now come to light.
明るみに出
Local police have started conducting an investigation.
現地の警察が 捜査に乗り出しています
♪ My dreams are not afraid to awaken; they continue to exist ♪
♪ 私の夢は覚めても消えない ♪
If judicial authorities determine
司法当局が 向梓に対する指摘の証拠が
that the evidence is sufficient to prove him guilty,
犯罪を立証するに 十分であると判断すれば
Xiang Zi will possibly face legal punishment.
向梓は法的責任を 問われる可能性があります
♪ I go beyond the dark clouds and feel the haze disperse ♪
♪ 雲の向こう 晴れ渡る ♪
Just as I pointed out before,
以前申し上げたとおり
in this case,
本件において
why was my client tagged
なぜ私の依頼人はいわれのない
with those unfounded labels?
レッテルを貼られたのか
Here's the reason.
その原因は
♪ Let me understand myself more clearly ♪
♪ 自分がもっと 見えてくる ♪
[A lesson on law by Mr. Lyu]
[呂弁護士の法律教育講座]
The society is constraining women
社会はステレオタイプな枠組みで
with stereotypical frameworks.
女性を縛りつけていることに あります
Beauty
美貌は
has become a sin.
原罪となり
♪ Take away my reflection ♪
♪ 私の面影をさらう ♪
Being talented is misinterpreted as being manipulative.
才能は腹黒いと曲解される
[A lesson on law by Mr. Lyu]
[呂弁護士の法律教育講座]
It is precisely these social prejudices
まさに こうした社会の偏見が
that restrict women's
女性の社会における
healthy development in this society
健全な発展を妨げています
and deprive women of the dignity
そして女性から本来あるべき尊厳を
they deserve.
奪っています
It's nice to live in a villa.
一軒家はいいけど
But one has to climb stairs.
階段を上るのがつらいな
Why don't you spend some money renovating the place,
お金を出してリフォームしない？
like installing an elevator?
エレベーターとかつけたら？
You really need some cardio exercise.
心肺機能を鍛えたほうがいいぞ
I knew you would say that.
そう言うと思った
No matter
どのような
what kind of adversity you are in,
苦境に陥っても
you are not fighting alone.
あなたは一人ではありません
You need to learn to
周りに助けを
-seek help from others. -Mr. Lyu's words are very powerful.
- 呂弁護士の言葉 力あるよな - 求めることも大切です
-Oh, right. -Only by countering the attacks head-on...
- そうだ - 正面から立ち向かうしか…
I've finished the preliminary process for the establishment
お前の女性法律支援基金の話だけど
of the legal aid fund for women that you're trying to set up.
初期手続きはほぼ終わらせた
The expense was too high, though.
でも 費用が結構かかったんだ
Money should go to where it's needed most.
お金は有意義に使うべきだ
I believe Mr. Lyu's words
呂弁護士の言葉は
Before the completion...
その前に
have made a very positive impression on the audience.
視聴者の皆さんに良い影響を 与えたと思います
Thank you so much.
本当にありがとうございました
Come on.
ほら
Rare for you to open a beer for me.
開けてくれるなんて珍しいな
Have you switched careers and become a drunkard now?
いつから飲んだくれになったんだ
Cheers!
乾杯
Don't drink alone.
一人で飲むな
Dad,
父さん
the boys you always talked about
いつも父さんが 気にかけてたみんなが
are here to visit you now.
会いに来たよ
[Tomb of Jiangjun, A Loving Father]
[慈父 蒋軍の墓]
Coach,
コーチ
we made it to the finals.
僕たち 決勝に進んだ
You said
コーチは言ったよな
we must treat you to hot pot when we won the tournament.
試合に勝ったら 火鍋をごちそうしろって
We've saved a place for you on the table.
だから ちゃんと用意した
Hope you wouldn't resent the spicy food.
辛いかもしれないけど
Jiang,
蒋コーチ
I wish you could
これからも
come watch us play again.
俺たちの試合を 見ていてくれたらよかったのに
Coach Jiang,
蒋コーチ
I can curve the ball really well now.
俺のカーブシュート すごくうまくなりました
It's a shame you can't see it now.
でも もう見てもらえないんですね
With or without your presence,
これからコーチがいなくても
we'll do our best in every game in the future.
俺たちは精一杯 サッカーを頑張ります
Coach...
コーチ
We're still together.
俺たちは解散してない
May you rest in peace in heaven.
そっちでゆっくりしていてください
[Tomb of Jiangjun, A Loving Father]
[慈父 蒋軍の墓]
Spend more time with Mr. Lin and Mrs. Lin
暇なら林のおじいさんと おばあさんと
playing chess or stuff there.
碁でも打ってください
Jiang,
蒋コーチ
we're all great football players now.
俺たち みんなすごく うまくなったんだ
You could boast about us everywhere.
絶対にコーチに自慢させてみせる
Jiang,
蒋コーチ
please don't take the nonsense
俺が前に言ったでたらめは
I said before to heart.
どうか気にしないでください
I was wrong.
俺が悪かったです
Jiang,
蒋コーチ
I've grown five more centimeters taller.
俺 また身長が５センチ伸びた
My vertical jump is three centimeters over the standard now.
それに垂直跳びも 目標より３センチ高く飛べる
In the past,
昔
we were silly
俺たちはバカで
and ignorant.
何も分からずに
We even hated you for leaving us behind.
見捨てられたって コーチを恨んでました
Coach,
コーチ
sorry.
すみません
Please don't be mad at us.
俺たちのこと 怒らないでください
Alright.
もういい
He would never be mad at you guys.
君たちを怒ったりしない
Instead, he would be proud of all of you.
君たちを誇りに思うはずだ
Coach Jiang,
蒋コーチ
we really miss you a lot.
本当に会いたいです
[Tomb of Jiangjun, A Loving Father]
[慈父 蒋軍の墓]
When did you come out here?
いつからそこにいたの？
There wasn't a sound at all.
声もかけずに
What wishes did you make?
何を願ってたんだ
Do you see the brightest star over there?
あの一番輝いてる星 見えた？
It's called Alioth.
あれは玉衡星よ
In childhood, my grandpa told me
小さい頃 おじいちゃんが言ってたの
that when I grew up,
私が大人になったら
he and grandma
おじいちゃんとおばあちゃんは
would move to that planet
あの星に一緒に住んで
as my guardian angels.
私を見守ってくれるって
Well...
じゃあ
What did you say to them?
２人に何を話したんだ
I told them that I won the case,
裁判に勝ったって報告して
and that they shouldn't worry anymore.
安心させたの
From now on,
これからは
my life will only get better and better.
もっといい人生を送るって
What else?
他には？
I also said...
あとは
I'd rather not tell you.
教えない
Never mind if you don't want to say it.
言いたくないならいいさ
Let's eat at my parents' place tomorrow.
明日 うちに食事に来いよ
Seriously, don't you think you two are dressed
おいおい こんなフォーマルな場に
too casually for such a formal occasion?
ずいぶんラフな格好じゃないか
Look at you.
それって
Really?
そうかな
But you are dressed quite formally.
あなたこそずいぶんフォーマルね
Are you going to propose marriage at my home, dressed like this?
そんな格好で うちに 結婚の申し込みでもするつもりか
Has Wang Tian agreed to marry you yet?
王天は受けてくれたのか
She will say yes sooner or later.
その日は いずれ来る
Come on.
行くぞ
Let's go home.
帰ろう
You're back, Fa.
小法 おかえり
Auntie Rong.
蓉さん
-This must be Wanxing, right? -Auntie Rong.
- こちらは晚星ですよね - 蓉さん
Change into the slippers over there.
そこにスリッパがあるから 履き替えて
Thanks.
ありがとう
Come on.
ほら
Dad!
父さん
Welcome.
ようこそ ようこそ
Hello, Uncle.
おじさん こんにちは
Ms. Lin, I was looking forward to your arrival.
林先生 首を長くして
Now, you're finally here.
待っていたぞ
Uncle, just call me Wanxing.
おじさん 私のことは星か 晚星と呼んでください
Sure, Wanxing.
星 星って呼ぶ
Uncle, call me Bo if you like.
おじさん 俺のことは 波って呼んでください
Why did you come here too?
なんでお前も来たんだ
Here you are, just a small gesture from me.
これ つまらないものですが
No, no. I don't eat junk like that.
いらん そんなわけの 分からんものは食わない
No, these are the latest products.
いや これは全部 最新の商品で
They bring great benefits to the elderly.
高齢者にすごくいいんですよ
What do you mean?
どういうつもりだ
Are you saying I'm very old now?
私が年寄りだと言いたいのか
No, I'm not. See, you're middle-aged and getting old.
いや おじさんは 年寄りじゃなくても
It's time you...
気をつけないと
-It's time for what? -For t-taking care
- 何だと？ - け 健康に
o-of your health.
け 健康に
Dad.
父さん
[Spicy wheat gluten strips]
[辣条]
Wanxing bought these spicy strips for you in secret.
これ 星がこっそり 父さんのために買ってきた辣条だよ
Really?
本当か
Listen, Uncle.
言っておきますけど おじさん
Spicy strips provides zero nutrition.
辣条は栄養がありませんよ
Look at this,
これを見てください
Reishi mushroom, the finest of its kind.
最高級の霊芝です
Forget about it.
もういい
My nose bled after eating
この前もらったものを
the stuff you gave me last time.
食べたら鼻血が止まらなくなった
Are you trying to get me hospitalized this time?
今度は私を病院送りにする気か
-Last time... -What about it?
前回のは…
What about it, huh?
前回のは何だ？
You just ate too much last time.
前回は食べ過ぎただけです
That was not really...
違いますって
How did you know I like spicy strips?
どうして私が辣条好きだって 分かったんだ
Wang Fa told me that.
王法に聞きました
See?
ほらな
Wanxing knows me so well.
やっぱり星は私を分かってくれる
Stash them for me.
これを隠しておいてくれ
Don't let your mother find them.
母さんに見つかるなよ
Rest assured.
任せといて
Uncle, these flowers are for you too.
おじさん このお花もどうぞ
Flowers too? How thoughtful of you.
花まで 気が利くな
I brought flowers as well.
俺も持ってきました
Look.
ほら
Still, lilies are better.
やはりユリがいい
Elegant and tasteful.
上品でセンスがある
Roses are just too tacky.
バラと違う 俗っぽくない
I have food cooking on the stove.
まだ火にかけたまま 料理してるんだよ
Listen, show Wanxing around the house.
星を連れて家の中を 案内してやってくれ
Or just take a rest.
休んでてもいい
I'll go make my signature dishes for you.
得意料理を作ってやるからな
-Alright. -Let me help you put these away.
- はいはい - 私が持ちましょう
Thanks for such hard work, Uncle.
お疲れ様です おじさん
Well, to be honest,
それもそうだな
it does take much hard work to make
私の娘に得意料理を作るなら
my signature dishes for my daughter.
骨を折らないとね
Not a problem at all.
もちろん問題ありません
I'll be your assistant.
手伝いは俺がやります
Are you sure you're up for it in this suit?
その格好で働けるのか
I can take it off.
脱げます
Let's get to work.
さあ
Y-You guys sit down.
星はまず座ってて
Be seated.
座って
You come with me.
来い
You've got this.
頑張って
Come on, I'll give you a tour.
行こう 案内するよ
Are you sure you can manage?
お前 大丈夫か
Yes!
大丈夫です
What is this?
これは何ですか
Feel free to browse.
好きに見ていいよ
Is this your room.
これはあなたの部屋？
I could tell that.
見れば分かるわ
What a spacious room.
この部屋 広いわね
Have you always looked so grumpy since you were little?
小さい頃から そんなに不愛想だったの？
It's just that my smiles are subtle.
笑い方が分かりにくかっただけだ
I have other photos.
他の写真もあるけど
Care to see them?
見るか
Sure.
見る
Is this you?
これ あなたなの？
I didn't know you used to be a chubby kid.
小さい頃は こんなにまん丸だったのね
It was thanks to my grandma.
おばあちゃんに たらふく食べさせられたからだ
My grandma's dream grandson
こうならないと
had to be well-fed and plump.
理想の孫じゃないんだって
Why is this photo still here?
なんでこんな写真があるんだ
Move your hand.
手をどけて
Let me see.
見せて
Is this also you,
これもあなたなの？
a boy in a princess dress?
プリンセスドレス
Little did I imagine you'd like
まさか小さい頃
to become a princess when you were little.
プリンセス願望があったなんて
This is the proof of me being persecuted by Wang Tian.
これは王天に迫害された証拠だ
Being persecuted?
迫害なの？
It seems to me the look suits you well.
すごく似合ってると思うけど
A pink bow.
ピンクのリボンに
A white tulle gown.
白いドレス
And those Mary Jane shoes.
それにメリージェーン
You look really cute in them.
すごくかわいい
Rainbow-like long hair,
虹色の長い髪と
with eyes resembling jewels.
宝石のような瞳
I think Her Highness the Shining Star Genius is even cuter.
キラキラ星の天才様のほうが かわいいよ
Why haven't you forgotten it?
まだ覚えてたの？
I just can't,
仕方ない
for she is so impressive and unforgettable
あれほど強烈な印象だったから
that the memory about her is still vivid in my mind.
忘れようにも忘れられないさ
Fine then.
分かったわ
It's fair to say we have seen each other's
じゃあ私たちはお互いの
embarrassing past.
黒歴史を知る仲ってことね
We're even now.
これでおあいこ
Why did you put on those red flowers?
なんで頭に赤い花をつけてるの？
It was all because I was persecuted by Wang Tian.
全部 王天のせいってことにしよう
You grew up to be quite a handsome guy, though.
大人になったら結構イケメンね
♪ There's nothing to fear ♪
♪ 何も怖くない ♪
♪ Because you're with me ♪
♪ 君がいるから ♪